<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Building a Containerized Web Application on AWS with CI/CD Pipeline on AWS System Manager</title><link>https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/</link><description>Recent content in Building a Containerized Web Application on AWS with CI/CD Pipeline on AWS System Manager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data encryption with AWS KMS</title><link>https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/4-securitymonitoring/4.1-aws-kms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/4-securitymonitoring/4.1-aws-kms/</guid><description>Introduction AWS Key Management Service (KMS) provides centralized encryption key creation and management, enabling data encryption both at rest and in transit. When combined with AWS Certificate Manager (ACM), the system can automatically manage the lifecycle of SSL/TLS certificates, including issuance, renewal, and deployment across AWS services.
For web applications deployed on EC2 with MongoDB Atlas databases, implementing KMS encryption ensures that sensitive information such as connection strings, user credentials, payment data, and personal information is protected at an enterprise level.</description></item><item><title>Create IAM Policies</title><link>https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/2-prerequiste/2.2-create-policies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/2-prerequiste/2.2-create-policies/</guid><description>Understanding IAM Policies ℹ️ What is an IAM Policy? An IAM Policy is a JSON document that defines permissions and access controls for AWS resources. These policies:
Define precise permissions for AWS services and resources Can be attached to IAM Users, Groups, and Roles Follow the principle of least privilege Enable fine-grained access control Policy Assignment ℹ️ How Policies Work IAM Policies provide the authorization framework by:
Defining allowed and denied actions Specifying resource-level permissions Supporting both AWS managed and customer managed policies Enabling conditional access based on tags, time, or location 🔒 Security Best Practices When working with IAM Policies:</description></item><item><title>Protect web applications with AWS WAF</title><link>https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/4-securitymonitoring/4.2-aws-waf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/4-securitymonitoring/4.2-aws-waf/</guid><description>Introduction AWS WAF (Web Application Firewall) is a powerful cloud security service designed to protect your web applications from common cyberattacks and malicious traffic. Operating at the application layer (Layer 7 of the OSI model), AWS WAF provides granular control over HTTP/HTTPS traffic to your application.
Why Use AWS WAF? In today&amp;rsquo;s increasingly complex cybersecurity landscape, web applications face various types of attacks:
SQL Injection: Attackers inject malicious SQL code into database queries</description></item><item><title>Monitor and automatically notify with CloudWatch and SNS</title><link>https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/4-securitymonitoring/4.3-aws-cloudwatch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thanhlong1512.github.io/Workshop-AWS/4-securitymonitoring/4.3-aws-cloudwatch/</guid><description>Introduction In today&amp;rsquo;s cloud environments, continuous monitoring and rapid incident response are critical factors determining application success. Amazon CloudWatch and Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS) form a powerful monitoring and alerting system that enables 24/7 application performance tracking and instant notifications when anomalies occur.
Amazon CloudWatch - The Eyes of AWS Infrastructure
Amazon CloudWatch is a comprehensive monitoring and observability service that provides visibility into all your AWS resources and applicationsạn Amazon SNS - Multi-Channel Notification System</description></item></channel></rss>